Where second best never gets a second chance.
Crossroads is a drama, music, mystery film directed by Walter Hill.
A wanna-be blues guitar virtuoso seeks a long-lost song
by legendary musician, Robert Johnson.
Eugene Martone, played by Ralph Macchio.
Willie Brown, played by Joe Seneca.
Frances, played by Jami Gertz.
Scratch's Assistant, played by Joe Morton.
Scratch, played by Robert Judd.
Jack Butler, played by Steve Vai.
Crossroads is a 1986 American musical drama film, inspired by
the legend of blues musician Robert Johnson.
It is directed by Walter Hill from a screenplay by John Fusco, and
stars Ralph Macchio, Joe Seneca and Jami Gertz.
It features an original score by Ry Cooder featuring classical guitar
by William Kanengiser and harmonica by Sonny Terry.
Steve Vai appears in the film as the devil's virtuosic
guitar player in the climactic guitar duel.
Fusco was a traveling blues musician prior to attending New York University Tisch School of the Arts, where
he wrote Crossroads as an assignment in a master class led by Waldo Salt and Ring Lardner Jr.
The student screenplay won first place in the national FOCUS Awards (Films of college and
University Students) and was sold to Columbia Pictures while Fusco was still a student.
The film was released by Columbia Pictures on March 14, 1986.
Although Crossroads received positive reviews from
critics, it was not a financial success.
However, it has been considered a cult classic,
particularly among musicians and guitarists.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.